MIKEL MATTICOLI

ENGINEER PRODUCER DESIGNER

SKILLS

Languages

Native: English, Spanish Proficient: French

Project Management 3



System Tools

Linux: Ubuntu, Debian, RHEL, bash, Ansible, cron, systemd, pam Windows: Powershell, AD/LDAP, Endpoint Manager MacOS: XCode, Homebrew Cloud: GCP, Azure, AWS, OpenShift, On-Premise/Self-Hosted Infrastructure DevOps: GitHub Actions, Jenkins

Software Development |

Version Control: Advanced Git, GitHub, GitHub Enterprise, Plastic SCM, Perforce (server admin, p4, p4v)

Docker: Local Dev & PaaS, compose

Platforms: Web (Full-Stack), Desktop, Android, iOS, AR/VR

Databases: MySQL, SQLite, Mongo, Firebase, GraphQL, Comdb2

Game Engines: Unity3D, Unreal Engine

Data Viz: Jupyter, Bokeh

Languages: Javascript, HTML/CSS, Python, C#, Java, Racket, Objective-C

Frameworks: React, Svelte, Express, Flask, Socket.IO, Parcel, Wordpress

SSO Integration: OAuth 2.0, OIDC,

Multimedia/Production

Office: MS Office, G Suite, VBA/GScript Video: Adobe Premier, After Effects Audio: Reaper, Adobe Audition, Mixcraft Image: Photoshop, GIMP, Inkscape 3D: Printing/Laser Cutting, Maya,

Fusion360, ZBrush

SAML, PRT

OVERVIEW

Engineer, producer, and designer with a passion for making things and helping people. I have 8 years of industry experience in software engineering, project management, IT, and experience design. I enjoy learning new skills and working with diverse teams to deliver polished projects that solve complex problems.

Portfolio: mikel.tech Email: mikel.matticoli@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/matticoli

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technology Consultant · Bloomberg LP

Jun 2018 - Present, Contract

- → Created and maintained web app template with built-in SSO and API docs, reducing initial dev time for new projects by 40%
- → Established docker-based local dev workflow to mirror production, reducing deployment overhead and streamlining on-boarding of new team members
- → Built interactive reports to show real-time and aggregated power/network usage data for critical hardware and software systems
- → Followed best practices for logging, CI/CD, and alarming to proactively identify and remediate potential client-affecting issues
- → Led R&D team building prototype VR/AR apps for use in datacenter operations

Senior Engineer (Full Stack + DevOps) · Intentional Design Studio Sep 2019 - Oct 2022, Contract

- → Created custom CI/CD & PaaS solution, cutting deployment times by 80% with zero overhead cost
- → Delivered 6 full-stack web apps and websites, from spec/design to maintenance phase, working solo or on teams of 3-6 devs, designers, & artists
- → Collaborated with various IT teams to ensure 99% uptime for all applications
- → Set up Perforce Helix Core server with LDAP and automated depot creation
- → Balanced dev work with project management, ensuring on-time and in-budget completion with 100% client satisfaction
- → Built cluster of 7 Ubuntu VMs from scratch, including automated package updates and service monitoring

Adjunct Instructor/Lecturer (IMGD) · Worcester Polytechnic Institute Aug 2022 - Oct 2022, Contract

- → Conducted lectures and lab activities to teach a class of 25 university students about game development, and provide hands-on experience with design, production, programming, art, and audio
- → Provided technical and instructional support to students using tools like Unity, GitHub, Raper, and Photoshop to create tightly scoped game projects
- → Maintained high level of student engagement, providing individual support as needed to ensure all engaged students met the learning goals of the course

MIKEL MATTICOLI

EDUCATION

MS, Interactive Media & Game Dev Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Focus Areas: Project Management & Experience Design

BS, Computer Science BS, Interactive Media & Game Dev Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Honors: High Distinction

Minor in Robotics Engineering

Minor in Media Art

CERTIFICATIONS

CITI Human Subjects Research Certification [CID: 33924155]

DEV204x: Programming with C#

MITx 6.00.1x: Intro to Computer Science and Programming Using Python

WORK SAMPLES

The Call of Karen

Award-winning PC simulator game about a 1950's housewife fighting Cthulhu (over 120,000 downloads on Steam).

https://callofkaren.com

JHDB Global Contributor Portal Accessible tool for the global jazz community to contribute historical artifacts to the Jazz History Database. https://global.jazzhistorydatabase.com

Rigs of Color Website

Project showcase/online store featuring art assets and tools for improving representation in media/games. https://rigsofcolor.com

See more cool projects on my website, these are just a few I enjoy talking about

Technical Director · Jazz History Database

Mar 2019 - Aug 2022, Part-Time

- → Designed, developed, and deployed custom content management app enabling non-technical correspondents around the world to contribute to the JHDB
- → Provided training and QA for ongoing multimedia and web dev work
- → Worked with non-technical stakeholders to identify key development needs
- → Led teams of students maintaining custom software using Agile methodologies

Programmer / Technical Artist · Trumbus Games

Jan 2019 - Jan 2021, Part-Time

- → Worked on a team of 4 to design, develop, and release a successful comedy PC simulation game about a 1950s housewife fighting meddling eldritch horrors
- → Implemented event/state and game save systems in Unreal Engine C++
- → Built level loading, localization, and gameplay systems using UE4 blueprint
- → Designed UI/menus and implemented art assets and animation in-engine

Project Manager • The Global Lab @ Worcester Polytechnic Institute Sep 2018 - Dec 2020, Part-Time

- → Worked with co-directors to establish production workflows and branding
- → Provided technical training and consulting services to students and faculty
- → Wrote and maintained intuitive and accessible documentation on media production software and equipment

Research Assistant (Bose AR) · WPI IMGD

Sep 2018 - Dec 2020, Part-Time

- → Created room-scale soundscape app using BoseAR SDK + ARCore in Unity
- → Presented research outcomes to engineering team at Bose Headquarters

Datacenter Intern · Bloomberg LP

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017, Internship

- → Participated in data center maintenance and operations, including hardware troubleshooting, infrastructure planning, and system monitoring
- → Developed internal web portal/API for monitoring datacenter power usage, as well as python scripts to automate repetitive maintenance tasks

Software Engineering Intern · SelfMade Co.

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015, Internship

- → Added several major features to an iMessage-like CRM web app
- → Implemented Slack integration, canned response/autocomplete and mobile UI

iOS Development Intern · UpSwerve Inc

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015, Internship

→ Added video capture/sharing features and various bug fixes for Snapchat-like app Camera Club, including both client and server-side implementation

Contact: mikel.matticoli@gmail.com

Portfolio: mikel.tech · LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/matticoli

References available upon request